Let's apply our knowledge of HTML to a real page.
我们将 HTML 知识应用于真实的网页
Here's a Wikipedia article.
这是维基百科的文章
I'll use my browser to see its source.
我将使用我的浏览器来查看它的源码
I'm using Google Chrome but every browser has a view source button.
我用的是 Google Chrome 但每个浏览器都有一个查看源代码选项
It just might not be in the same place as it is in Chrome.
它可能跟 Chrome 不在同一个地方显示
This HTML isn't as tidy as the example we looked at before.
这个 HTML 代码并不像之前的示例那样整洁
Unlike Python, HTML doesn't require indentation or organization.
与 Python 不同 HTML 不需要缩进或组织代码
If you scroll through it though we can see some familiar tags.
但是如果你往下拉 我们还是可以看到一些熟悉的标签
Here's a paragraph, some divs and some a herf tags.
这是一个段落标签 一些 div 标签和一些 a herf 标签
Let's switch back to the rendered version of the page.
让我们切换回渲染版本的网页
Okay, the first link in the page is this link to the Monty Python article.
好的 页面中的第一个链接是指向 Monty Python 文章的链接
Let's try to find that in the source code.
我们尝试在源代码中找到它
Here it is. It looks like the article's text begins right here.
在这里 看起来文章的文字从这里开始
This link is inside a paragraph tag,
此链接在一个段落标签内部
but I can't really tell if the paragraph tag is inside of any other tags.
但是我无法确定段落标签是否还在其他标签内
There's just too much unformatted HTML for me to read.
有太多无格式的 HTML 了 没办法阅读
Fortunately, browsers have tools to make this manageable.
幸运的是 浏览器具有管理工具
I want to close this source code tab and open the developer tools.
我要关闭这个源代码选项卡 并打开开发者工具
These developer tools aren't unique to Chrome.
开发者工具 不是 Chrome 独有的
Every browser has something similar.
每种浏览器都有类似的东西
Okay, now we have an organized view of the HTML.
好的 现在我们有一个有组织的 HTML 视图
I can right click the first link and choose Inspect.
我可以右键单击第一个链接并选择检查
Then the tree of elements in the Tools panel
然后工具面板中的元素树
expands to show the hierarchy of tags that lead to the link.
展开来显示链接所在标签的层次结构
It looks like the first link is this a herf tag which is inside of this paragraph tag,
看起来 第一个链接是这个段落标签内的一个 a herf 标签
which is inside of this div.
段落标签在这个 div 标签内
The div's ID is mw-content-text.
div 的 ID 是 mw-content-text
It looks like that div is inside of a chain of a few more divs.
看起来这个 div 还有几个并列的 div
Excellent, if every article is structured like this one,
非常好 如果每篇文章都是这样的结构
then we should be able to use this information to do our web crawler.
那么我们应该可以使用这些信息 来做我们的网页抓取工具